Guide to the William J. Minor Horse Racing Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
William J. Minor horse racing papers
1815-1866
GEN MSS 304
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.8
(3 boxes)
Contains letters to Minor regarding horse racing and horse pedigrees, including letters from Cadwallader R. Colden and Sanders Dewees Bruce; notes on horse races and pedigrees; proceedings of the Natchez Jockey Club, of which Minor was secretary; manuscript articles about horses, possibly by Minor; and an obituary for Minor from "Turf, Field, and Farm."
Minor, William J., 1807-1869
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. David Wagstaff, 1951 and 1954.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 3: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Scope and Contents
This finding aid encompasses accessions of materials pertaining to William J. Minor and horse racing.
Horse racing -- Mississippi; Horses -- Mississippi -- Pedigrees; Race horses -- Mississippi; Natchez (Miss.); Bruce, Sanders Dewees, 1825-1902; Colden, Cadwallader R., 1774-1839; Minor, William J., 1807-1869; Natchez Jockey Club
- Correspondence, Series I
  - LETTERS TO WILLIAM J. MINOR
    - Alderson, Thomas, 1848-53 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alexander, R. Aitcheson, 1856, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bruce, Sanders Dewees, 1858 Jun 23 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Clay, John M., 1865 Mar 15 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Colden, Cadwallader R., 1833-36 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Comptens, Henry, 1852 Sep 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Duncan, H. J., 1841 Nov 21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Elliott, George
      Related Archival Materials note
      See: G. B. Williams, Box 1, folder 26
    - Farris, H. W., 1863 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Gray, D. L., [18]56 Apr 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Gross, Joseph R., 1857-60 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Grunstead, James A., 1836-57 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Hughes, J. J., 1844, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Jackson, James, 1839 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Lewis, Hickman
    - McGehee, D. L., 1866 Apr 30 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Minor, Henry C., 1863 Nov 23 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Minor, Stephen, 1864, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Morgan, Rolley
    - Odom, Eli, [1848] Aug 10 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - [Payors?], G. B., [18]57 Mar 25 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Peck, Jeffrey
    - Peirce, Grenville N., [18]66 Apr 22 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Peters, A. G.
      See: Thomas T. Smith, Box 1, folder 22
    - Porter, W. J., 1845 Jul 24 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Richards, A. Keene, 1858 Jun 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Smith, Thomas T., 1859 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Scope and Contents
      Also signed by A. G. Peters.
    - Spencer, Joseph, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Tattersall, R., 1835-38 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Thomas, George, 1834 Oct 3 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Williams, G. B., 1841-49 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - THIRD PARTY LETTERS
    - Minor, L. to John Minor, 1815 Dec 22 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Notes and Notebooks, Series II
  - [Horses. Physical descriptions of], manuscript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - [Lists of blood stock], manuscript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Mem[oranda] of the Time Made by Various Horses Over Various Courses in the M[etairie] J[ockey Club]," holograph, 1837-60 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Includes clippings pasted in.
  - [Pedigree. Notes on], manuscript, 1833-44, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Private Trials," holograph, 1830-44 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Private Trials," holograph, 1836-58 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Proprietors of Metairie Race Course Organizing a Club," manuscript, 1856 Apr 7 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Record of the Proceedings of the Natchez Jockey Club," holograph, 1836-47 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Minor was Secretary. Includes clipping pasted in.
  - "Time of the Races Run at New Orleans and Elsewhere," holograph, 1835-49 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - "Vandyke," holograph, 1858-60 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - [Waterloo Track times], holograph, 1836-62 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Other, 1857 Jan 30; Series III
  - Agreement, manuscript, signed by Minor, to train Mr. Peters' horse, 1857 Jan 30 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Articles, manuscript, regarding horses, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
    Possibly written by Minor.
  - Clipping (annotated) regarding horse race on 1859 Dec 16, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Obituary for Minor, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 43)
    From Turf, Field, and Farm, 1869 Oct 22.
- Restricted Fragile Papers
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 3: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 1 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Box 1, folder 12 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Box 1, folder 13 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Box 1, folder 19 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Box 1, folder 28 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Box 1, folder 31 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Box 2, folder 40 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Box 2, folder 41 (Box 3, Folder 51)